Guide to the Bert Morgan Photographic Negatives circa 1932-1963, 1981 (bulk, 1960-1961) PR 367
New-York Historical Society
Bert Morgan photographic negatives
circa 1932-1963, 1981 (bulk, 1960-1961)
New-York Historical Society
Morgan, Bert, 1904-1986
Morgan, Richard, 1936-2012
PR 367
3.41 Linear Feet (approximately 801 negatives and 18 glass plates in 4 boxes)
Approximately 819 black-and-white photographic negatives (18 of which are glass plates) by celebrity and society photographer Bert Morgan (1904–1986) and his son/assistant, Richard Morgan (1936–2012), documenting charity balls, weddings, the annual dog show of the Westminster Kennel Club, and the opening of the National Horse Show, at Manhattan venues such as the Waldorf-Astoria, Madison Square Garden, and Lüchow's restaurant.
Arrangement
The collection is housed in four boxes. Boxes 1-3 hold dated negatives in chronological order, with undated negatives at the end. Due to the possible combustibility of some of these negatives, boxes 1-3 are kept in cold storage. Requests for this portion of the collection must allow at least one full day for it to thaw.
Box 4 holds 18 glass plate negatives. These must not be removed from their four-flap protective enclosures. To view a plate, place it flat on the surface of a lightbox and open its enclosure.
Biographical Note
By most accounts Bert Morgan (1904–1986) was the dean of society photographers. Between the 1930s and 1980s, wherever the wealthy and notable gathered—New York, Southampton, Newport, or Palm Beach—Morgan was there to photograph them at charity balls, banquets, horse shows, and weddings.
Born Bernard Stanley Morgan in England in 1904, "Bert" emigrated with his family to the United States in 1911 and settled in Brooklyn, New York. With a seven-dollar pawn shop camera he began working as a syndicate news photographer in 1919. For a decade Morgan supplied northeastern papers like the New York Daily News with images of the common man. In 1930 he became the official photographer for the Social Spectator. The paper sent Morgan to Palm Springs that winter to capture New York celebrities at play, launching his fifty-year career of documenting their progress from the "Four Hundred" to "Café Society" to the "Jet Set." His son, Richard Morgan (1936–2012), also a photographer, eventually assisted.
Morgan's modus operandi was to position his camera and tripod at some heavily-trafficked hotspot, be it nightclub or racetrack (he was the official photographer for the New York Racing Association) to shoot luminaries as they went by. His gentlemanly demeanor and encyclopedic memory endeared him to his subjects: he could identify thousands of them by name and residence simply by looking at their pictures. At his death Morgan left 1.5-million negatives. Some 500,000 of them make up the Bert Morgan Archive, administered by Archive Farms, Inc.
[This note is drawn from Morgan's obituary in the Palm Beach Daily News, Sunday 21 September 1986, and from information in South Hampton Blue Book 1930 to 1960: Photographs by Bert Morgan (Shelter Island, N.Y.: Archive Farms, Inc., 2014).]
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Due to the possible combustibility of some of the negatives in boxes 1-3, that portion of the collection is kept in cold storage. Requests to view boxes 1-3 must allow at least one full day for them to thaw.
The 18 glass plate negatives in the collection must not be removed from their four-flap protective enclosures. To view a plate, place it flat on the surface of a lightbox and open its enclosure.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Patrick Montgomery, May 2017.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains approximately 563 sleeves, each holding one or more 4-by-5-inch black-and-white photographic negatives, for an approximate total of 801. A handful of strip film negatives are in color (see the envelope in the back of box 3). And eighteen are 4-by-5-inch glass plate, black-and-white negatives (see box 4).
Each sleeve (or envelope) carries typed or handwritten information supplied by the photographer, usually the event, the location, the date, and the names of his subjects. A very few sleeves hold prints of negatives, and some include typed captions, business cards, and the occasional newsclipping.
Although Bert Morgan photographed celebrities and socialites at their far-flung haunts, the venues in the current collection are limited to locations in Manhattan: the ballrooms of the Americana, Astor, Plaza, Sheraton-East, and Waldorf-Astoria hotels; the churches of St. Bartholomew, St. Ignatius Loyola, and Fifth Avenue Presbyterian; famous eateries like Lüchow's and the Four Seasons; Madison Square Garden; the Museum of the City of New York; and Bloomingdale's department store.
A majority of the events depicted were charity balls. Besides raising money for some worthy cause, the gatherings provided luminaries with a platform to be seen—and photographed. Morgan's record of his subjects on his negative sleeves (see the container list) reads like a "Who's Who" of late 1950s- early 1960s society, and includes actresses (Eva Gabor), designers (Oleg Cassini), diplomats (Porfirio Rubirosa), foreign dignitaries (Pratap Singh Rao Gaekwad, Maharajah of Baroda), minor royalty (Princess Stephanie of Windisch-Graetz), and the fabulously wealthy (Cornelius Vanderbilt Whitney). As many of these charity balls took place during the early 1960s, it is not surprising that "the Twist" makes several appearances in the collection. Morgan notes several couples "doing the Twist." The dance craze was so widespread that at least one fundraiser at the staid Four Seasons was billed as a "twist party" (see box 3, folder 2).
Earlier in his career Morgan documented the dog shows of the Westminster Kennel Club at Madison Square Garden (see box 1, folders 4, 5, and 12), and the annual openings of the National Horse Show (box 1, folder 8, and box 2, folder 5 and box 3, folder 1), considered to be the start of the social calendar.
Black-and-white negatives; Color negatives; Glass negatives; Balls (Parties) -- New York (State) -- New York; Dogs -- Photographs.; Upper class -- New York (State) -- New York -- Portraits; Four Seasons (Restaurant); Luchow's (Restaurant: New York, N.Y.); Hotel Astor (New York, N.Y.); Madison Square Garden (New York, N.Y.: 1925-1968); Plaza Hotel (New York, N.Y.); Sheraton-East Hotel (New York, N.Y.); Waldorf-Astoria Hotel (New York, N.Y.); Westminster Kennel Club. Dog Show
- St. Ignatius Loyola, New York, N.Y. [1 negative in 1 sleeve], [1933 May 24] (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Subject:
  Wedding of Mr. and Mrs. Richard Markey Egan. (Bride daughter of Maj. Gen. and Mrs. Wm. N. Haskell; groom son of Mr. and Mrs. Charles E. Egan.)
- McCann Garden Party [1 negative in 1 sleeve], 1934 June 26 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Subjects:
  Pruyn, Julie
  Sorcester, Mrs. Wakefield
  Washburn, Mrs. Wm. Ives
- [individuals] [1 negative in 1 sleeve], 1935 or 1937 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Bloomer, J. Ralph
  Lowell, Mrs. James R.
  Shaw, Lawrence Copley and Mrs.
- Westminster Kennel Club [59 negatives in 55 sleeves], 1937 February 10–12 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Sixty-first annual Westminster Kennel Club Dog Show, held at Madison Square Garden.
  Afghan Hound, "Hari of Pride Hill" (owner Q. A. Shaw McKean)
  Airdale Terrier, "Sheterock Merry Soverign" (owner S. M. Stewart)
  Belgian Sheepdog, "Haagi du Chemin Des Dames" (owner Fabienne Lloyd)
  Borzoi / Russian Wolfhound, "Vigow of Romanoff" (owner Louis Murr)
  Boston Terrier, "Holiday Chummy" (owner Hilda Ridder [?] with Henry Lyuties)
  Boxer, "Dorian von Marienhoff of Mazelaine" (owner John Phelps Wagner)
  Bulldog, "Charminster Son O'Sandy" (owner Mrs. Richard Trinisei[?])
  Cardigan Welsh Corgi, "Lleethferch" (owner Mrs. B.P. Bole)
  Chihuahua, "Cecilee of Etty Haven" (owner Mrs. H. Proctor Donnell Reilly)
  Chihuahua, "Clarke's Leona" (owner Clarke's Kennels)
  Dachshund, "Midge von Edelhof" (owner Mr. and Mrs. Wm. E. Schmidt)
  Doberman Pinscher, "Falko von Lindenhoff" (owner C. W. Bradley)
  English Bull, "Dietrich Dracula" (owner Mrs. Biancia Dietrich)
  English Setter, "Pilot of Crombie" (owner Dr. A. A. Mitten)
  Greyhound, "White Rose of Boveway" (owner Harry T. Peters Jr.)
  Irish Water Spaniel, "King Erin" (owner Mrs. Thomas C. Marshall)
  Japanese Spaniel, "Mo-Mo" (owner Mrs. Lida E. Domler)
  Pug, "Torch of Red Gate"
  Pekingese, "Tang Hao of Coversham Catawba" (owner Mrs. James M. Austin)
  St. Bernard, "Esbo Von," "Grossylockner Von Edelweiss" (owner Edelwiess Kennels)
  Samoyede, "Norkas Viking" (owner Norkas Kennels)
  Westhighland White, "Edgerstonne Roughy" (owner Mrs. John G. [S.?] Winant)
  Wire Haired Dachshund, "Tess of Tynewydd" (owner George Frelinghuysen Jr.)
  Wire Haired Terrier, "Flornell Spicy Piece of Halleston" (owner Stanley Halle)
- New York Hound Show [14 negatives in 14 sleeves], 1937 February 12 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Held at Madison Square Garden in conjunction with the final day of the Westminster Kennel Club Dog Show (see box 1, folder 4).
  Cheshire Hounds
  Essex Fox Hounds ("Bachelor"; "Taylor")
  Rombout Hunt ("Crusty"; "Crazy"; "Julia"; "Fancy")
  Vernon-Somerset Beagles
- Champagne Ball [1 negative in 1 sleeve], 1940 October 25 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Champagne Ball and Debutante Cotillion given at the Waldorf-Astoria for the benefit of the New York Infirmary for Women and Children.
  Faber, Blaine
  Johnson, Josephine
- Bundles for Britain [Ball, Waldorf-Astoria] [4 negatives in 4 sleeves], 1940 November 7 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  "Bundles for Britain," an organization of knitting circles begun in 1940 by Natalie Wales Latham, shipped socks, gloves, hats, sweaters, and scarves to war-torn Britain. This ball, held at the Waldorf-Astoria in conjunction with the opening of the National Horse Show, featured a raffle for a cigarette case donated by Queen Elizabeth.
  Creel, J. Randall and Mrs.
  Curtis, Pauline
  McDonnell, James F. Jr.
  Russell, Louise (daughter of Mrs. A. D. Russell; member of Debutante Guard of Honor)
- National Horse Show [41 negatives in 41 sleeves], 1940 November 8–12 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Alexandre, Mrs. Frederick F.
  Anderson, Joan
  Barry, Coralie
  Beguelin, Taylor
  Briggs, Jane
  Cecil, Amanda
  Dobbs, Mrs. Wm.
  Duke, Mrs. St. George
  Dunn, Patricia
  Goodman, Robert and Mrs.
  Gosselin, Robert Thomas
  Grove, Wallace J. and Mrs.
  Hurry [?], Philip
  Jennings, Kathleen
  Kavanagh, Joseph Jr.
  Kees, Mrs. Walter
  Klysstein [Klipstein?], Peggy
  Loucks, Marion
  Luckenbach, Com. Edgar F.
  McCormack, Julie
  McDonnell, Lawrence
  Melville, Margaret
  Renwick, Mrs. Thomas
  Rosonquet, Mary
  Ruxton, Wm. V. C.
  Scott, Mrs. Robert L.
  Sherman, George Carter
  Treat, John
  Van Alen, Sammy
  Van Sinderen, Adrian
  Wagstaff, Mrs. David
  Wahl, Barbara
  Walbridge, Mary
  Warner, Ira Follett and Mrs.
  Weber, Clare
- 99 Ball [4 negatives in 4 sleeves], 1940 November 8 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Cochran, Jacqueline
  Francis, Mrs. Devon
  Gillies, B. Allison and Mrs.
  Kenyon, Mrs. Theodore
  Seversky, Alexander P. de
- Easter Sunday [2 negatives in 2 sleeves], 1942 April 5 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Gerard, James W. and Mrs.
  Sykes, Mrs. Prince
  Winkhause, Corporal John T.
- [individuals] [1 negative in 1 sleeve], 1944 September 4 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Campbell, Frank and Mrs. (née Eleanor Gallagher)
- Westminster Kennel Club [1 negative in 1 sleeve], 1945 February 12–13 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Sixty-ninth annual Westminster Kennel Club Dog Show, held at Madison Square Garden.
  Pembroke Welsh Corgi, "Deb of Greencorg" (owner Mrs. H. L. Green)
- Opera [1 negative in 1 sleeve], 1947 November 11 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Opening of the 63rd season of the Metropolitan Opera (then located at 1411 Broadway between 39th and 40th Streets).
  Chrysler, Walter P. Jr. and Mrs.
  Dick, Wm. K. and Mrs.
  McLanahan [?], Alexander and Mrs.
- National Horse Show, Madison Square Garden, New York [2 negatives in 1 sleeve], 1951 November (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Van Lennup, Frederick
- Fan Ball - Astor Hotel [2 negatives and 1 print in 2 sleeves], [between 1954-1961] (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Cavanagh, Edward F. Jr. (Fire Commissioner) [served 1954-1961]
  Fagan, Paul III
  Guest, Gail
  Havemeyer, Ruth
- Flamingo Ball, Waldorf Astoria [5 negatives in 5 sleeves], 1956 November 9 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Benefit for the Soldiers', Sailors', Marines', Coast Guard and Airmen's Club (283 Lexington Avenue, Manhattan).
  Baroda, Maharajah of (Pratap Singh Rao Gaekwad)
  Fisher, Mrs. Alfred J. Jr.
  Gimbel, Bernard F.
  Luro, Mrs. Horatio A.
  Obolensky, Colonel Serge
  Sanford, Mrs. Stephen
  Tansill, Mrs. Donald
  Wagner, Mrs. Robert (wife of NYC mayor)
  Wright, Cobina Sr.
- Park Ave – Easter Sunday [1 negative and 1 print in 1 sleeve], 1960 [April 17] (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Cox, Edward
  Cox, Howard and Mrs.
  Cox, Howard Jr.
  Cox, Mary Ann
- Salute to Spring, Italian Renaissance Ball, Plaza [33 negatives in 28 sleeves], 1961 April 19 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Benefit by the Renaissance of Italian Youth Foundation for the orphanage of San Domenico in Picanello, Sicily. Includes a typed, alphabetized guest list.
  Boardman, T. Dennie
  Boythan, Stephan van and Mrs.
  Buitoni, Giovanni and Mrs.
  Cassini, Mrs. Igor
  Chisholm, Hugh J. and Mrs. (former Rosemary Warburton)
  Chisholm, Mrs. Hugh Jr.
  Cowell, Richard
  Drexel, Mrs. John R. 3rd
  Farr, Mrs. Francis
  Fontaine, Joan
  Gardiner, Robert D. L. and Mrs.
  Garrett, Paul and Mrs.
  Graham, Mrs. Elizabeth N. (Elizabeth Arden)
  Javits, Eric M.
  Johnson, Warren and Mrs.
  Kent, Suzanne (daughter of A. Atwater Kent Jr.)
  Langley, Mrs. Wm. C.
  Melhado, Mrs. Frederick
  Messmore, Carman and Mrs.
  Muss, Mrs. David
  Pell, John H. G. and Mrs.
  Ren, Count Vega Del
  Riebenfeld, Mrs. Paul
  Rybar, Valerian Stux
  Santry, Louise
  Schell, Philip O'R.
  Smith, Mrs. Earl E. T.
  Treat, John A. and Mrs.
  Tuck, Mrs. Frederick W. 3rd (Cheray Zauderer)
  Vroom, Jan De
  Zaccour, Jose
- Bloomingdale's L'Esprit de France [14 negatives in 4 sleeves], 1961 September 26 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Reception for Bloomingdale's store-wide presentation of French merchandise. Includes a letter inviting Morgan to photograph the ticket-only event.
  Cromwell, Mrs. James H. R.
  Dickinson, Edward T. (president, New York Racing Association)
  Langdon, Louise [photographs taken for]
  Ryle, Joseph (vice president, Thomas J. Deegan Co.)
- Aqueduct [Racetrack] [2 negatives in 1 sleeve], 1961 October 7 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  Thibault, Mrs. Conrad (Dee Bredin)
- Hope Ball, Waldorf-Astoria [44 negatives 28 sleeves], 1961 October 17 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  Annual benefit to support the Institute for Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation of New York University Medical Center.
  Ashton, Charles
  Bancroft, Mrs. Thomas M. Jr. (Melissa Weston, model in "Sophie's" fashion show)
  Bartholow, Mrs. E. Boggs
  Boythan, Stefan Van, Count and Countess
  Carnevale, Don V. (vice president, Harry Winston, Inc.)
  Clark, John C. and Mrs.
  Cortney, Mrs. Philip (General chairman, Hope Ball)
  Craigmyle, Ronald and Mrs.
  Dalva, David Leon and Mrs.
  Davis, Mrs. John
  Dresselhuys, Cornelius and Mrs.
  Erpf, Armand G.
  Feldman, Mrs. George
  Gibbons, J. L. and Mrs.
  Hood, Clifford and Mrs.
  Johnson, William F. B. and Mrs.
  Ludwig, Daniel K. and Mrs.
  Maguire, Mrs. Jeremiah D.
  Melhado, Frederick and Mrs.
  Meyer, Mrs. Francine
  Muss, David and Mrs.
  Nelson, Herbert and Mrs.
  Orssich, Vincent, Count and Countess
  Robinson, Joseph W. and Mrs.
  Roebling, Mrs. Siegfried
  Sachar, Louis and Mrs.
  Snell, Lawrence W. and Mrs.
  Spencer, Percival G. and Mrs. (the president, Sinclair Oil Company)
  Statt, Robert L. and Mrs.
  Strelitz, Mrs. J. Malcolm
  Tansill, Donald
  Thomas, Edmund E. and Mrs.
  Towbin, Belmont and Mrs.
- April in Paris Ball [57 negatives in 41 sleeves], 1961 October 20 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  The tenth annual April in Paris Ball, a benefit for the French Hospital in New York City, and for the charities represented by the American French Foundation. Held at the Seventh Regiment Armory.
  Amor, Mohamed Ben Ambassador of Morocco to Switzerland, and Mrs.
  Arpels, Mrs. Helene
  Bertrand, Henri
  Bostwick, Albert C. Jr. and Mrs.
  Branton-Birnbaum, Timothy and Mrs. (former Michelle Clark)
  Buitoni, Mrs. Bruno
  Carnevale, Donald V.
  Chalk, O. Roy
  Coleman, E. B.
  Coulson, Mrs. Richard
  Cromwell, James H. R.
  Cummings, Nathan and Mrs.
  Cutton, Mrs. Jennie
  Dodge, Mrs. Horace E. 2nd (née "Gregg Sherwood")
  Evans, Charles and Mrs.
  Fenelon-Young, Mrs. Sally
  Garbisch, Edgar and Mrs. (former Bernice Chrysler)
  Gosselin, Edward M.
  Gropper, Edward and Mrs.
  Grossman, Harold and Mrs. (former Florence Lustig)
  Jellown, Abdel Kader Ben (H.E. Minister of Labor and Social Affairs of Morocco)
  Johnson, F. Raymond and Mrs.
  Kelley, Solon and Mrs.
  Landon, Clarisse
  Lawrence, Francis "Bunty" and Mrs.
  Levitt, Mrs. Alfred P.
  Loehman, Charles C. and Mrs.
  Meyers, Philip
  Milley, Herbert and Mrs. (he Pan American Air Lines)
  Mitchell, Jan and Mrs. (owner of Lüchow's)
  Moran, Daniel
  Munn, Orson D. Jr. and Mrs.
  Saunders, Marion
  Schmidlapp, Horace and Mrs.
  Shirley, Walter T. Jr.
  Spingold, Mrs. Nathan (Frances)
  Sticca, Roland
  Taub, William L.
  Timmins, Edwin F. Russell Robert and Mrs.
  Vandable, Louis
  Vickrey, Claude C.
  Vignos, Mimi
  Whitlock, Emmet and Mrs.
  Wolfson, Cecil and Mrs.
- At Lüchow's [39 negatives in 26 sleeves], 1961 October 21 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  The legendary Lüchow's restaurant at 110 East 14th Street, Manhattan, catered to celebrity clientele for a century (1882–1983). A newspaper clipping filed with one of Morgan's negatives explains the reason for this particular gathering was to celebrate the recent birth of Lüchow's owner Jan Mitchell's son, David.
  Barclay, Mrs. Lyda
  Berns, Charles A. and Mrs.
  Brown, Mrs. Richard (Eva Gabor)
  Byfield, Mrs. Ernest
  Carter, Jack and Mrs. (former Paula Stewart)
  Dever, Joseph
  Hall, Randolph
  Hammer, Victor
  Hunt, Barbara Dunne
  Isles, Mrs. Philip
  Ittleson, Mrs. Henry
  Kazner, Kurt
  Kent, Joan
  Lamkin, Marguerite
  Munn, Mrs. Orson D.
  Nelson, Herbert K. and Mrs.
  Newhouse, Clyde and Mrs. (former Maggi McNellis)
  Scott-Duff, Peggy
  Seghers, Paul and Mrs.
  Shen, Tai
  Smart, Mrs. David (Gabrielle, owner of Esquire Magazine)
  Solinger, David and Mrs. (former Hope Gimbel)
  Stephenson, Garrick and Mrs.
  Straile, Robert
  Styne, Jule
- United Hunts Ball, Hotel Plaza [36 negatives in 29 sleeves], 1961 October 26 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Annual presentation of the Martini and Rossi Point-to-Point trophies at the Dinner-Dance of the United Hunts Racing Association.
  Bostwick, George H. "Pete"
  Cavalchini, Gregory (of Martini and Rossi)
  Clark, Mrs. Stephen C. Jr.
  Cocks, W. Burling
  Duvall, Virginia M.
  Dixon, Eugene Jr. and Mrs.
  Gould, Kingdon
  Gubelmann, Walter S. and Mrs.
  Haskell, Amory L. and Mrs. (the president, United Hunts)
  Hulitar, Philip and Mrs.
  Jacobs, Hirsch and Mrs.
  Jacobs, Patrice M.
  Jeffords, Walter M. Jr. and Mrs.
  Kusner, Kathy
  Langley, Mrs. William C. (former Jane Pickens)
  McKim, Mary Maud (daughter of Mrs. Ogden Phipps)
  Mills, Phyllis
  Ohrstrom, George L. Jr. and Mrs.
  Ohrstrom, Mrs. Ricard
  Perry, William Haggin and Mrs. (former Kathryn von Stade)
  Phipps, Mrs. Ogden
  Scott, Maxwell L. and Mrs. (the vice president, Cross and Brown Co.)
  Smith, Crompton
  Stern, Allison L. S.
  Sweet-Escott, Nancy
  Tippett, Cloyce and Mrs. (former Liz Whitney)
  Trout, Thaddeus and Mrs.
  Watters, Sidney Jr.
  Wettach, Michael
- Fan Ball, Hotel Plaza, New York [65 negatives in 46 sleeves], 1961 October 27 (Box 2, Folder 4.1-4.2)
  Benefit for the Children's Cancer Fund of America.
  Balcom, Mrs. Ronald
  Ballard, Mrs. John
  Bassett, Theodore "Ted"
  Bell, John C. and Mrs.
  Brady, Philip H. and Mrs. (former Lulu Vanderbilt, daughter of late George Vanderbilt)
  Burden, W. Douglas Jr.
  Butler, Mrs. Michael (daughter-in-law of Paul Butler)
  Dwight, Mrs. Harvey
  Fonda, Susan
  Freimann, Mrs. Lorraine Gallagher
  Gavin, Mrs. Vasco
  Giddens, Zambry P. and Mrs. (the vice president, Dynamics Corporation of America)
  Gropper, Edward J.
  Hailparn, Mrs. Albert
  Harrison, William
  Herron, Anita
  Hickox, John B.
  Hynes, Eugene J.
  Jaffe, William B. and Mrs.
  Johnstone, Edmund F. and Mrs. (former Janet Olcott)
  Kiebech, Walter W.
  Kogel, Mercedes de
  Lagerwall, Gabrielle
  Lindfors, Viveca (actress)
  Martin, Dawson
  McKinley, William
  Moloney, Herbert and Mrs.
  Moore, Aurora
  Morford, Gordon and Mrs.
  Mundin, Mrs. Herbert T. (president, Fan Ball)
  Ong, Mrs. Eugene
  Oppenheim, August Rust
  Orsini, Armand and Mrs.
  O'Toole, James
  Perera, Lionel C. Jr. and Mrs.
  Pierson, Mrs. William
  Roberts, Alfred and Mrs.
  Robinson, Mrs. Gladys (formerly Mrs. Edward G. Robinson)
  Ryan, John Barry
  Schrafft, George
  Shaffer, Charles N. and Mrs.
  Strelsin, Mrs. Alfred
  Tuck, Frederick W. 3rd and Mrs. (former Cheray Zauderer)
  Tuck, Mrs. Frederick W. Jr.
  Van Gilder, John S.
  Vickrey, Claude
  Weisner, Sidney D. and Mrs.
  White, Paul J. and Mrs. (the president, Westchester C.C.N.Y.)
  Williams, Mrs. L. Clark
  Wrangel, Baron George
  Zauderer, George and Mrs.
- National Horse Show, Madison Square Garden [23 negatives in 18 sleeves], 1961 October 31 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Barrett, Margot
  Cavanagh, Barbara
  Cavanagh, Frank B. and Mrs. (former Marcia Murray)
  Cromwell, James H. R. and Mrs.
  Gardiner, Robert D. L. and Mrs. (former Eunice Oakes)
  Gavin, Mme. Vasco
  Haskell, Amory L. and Mrs.
  Howley, General Frank
  Leness, Mrs. George
  Levings, Commander Nelson Trimble and Mrs.
  Lewis, Henry 3rd and Mrs.
  Melville, Ward
  Parish, Mrs. R. Laurence
  Smith, Mrs. Homer
  Stitzer, Charles W. 3rd
  Swett, Robert
  Wareham, James M.
  Webster, Reginald N. and Mrs.
  Zauderer, Pamela (daughter of Mr. and Mrs. George Zauderer)
- 1860 Ball at Museum City of N.Y. [23 negatives in 18 sleeves], 1961 November 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Benefit at and for the Museum of the City of New York recreating the fete that welcomed the Prince of Wales (later Edward VII) to New York City in 1860.
  Aspegren, Mrs. John B.
  Bacon, Isabelle
  Dean, Sir Patrick and Lady (British Representative, United Nations)
  Fooshee, Malcolm and Mrs.
  Goddard, Russell
  Goddard, Sarah
  Gowing, Gene
  Gubelmann, Mrs. Walter S.
  Macy, J. Noel and Mrs. (he in Civil War Uniform)
  Miller, Ralph
  Munn, Mrs. Orson D. Jr.
  Paine, Mrs. Peter Standish
  Rhinelander, T. J. Oakley
  Rose, Mrs. Reginald P. (vice president, Museum of the City of New York)
  Steinway, Mrs. Frederick
  Sullivan, John McNamee and Mrs.
  Van Rensselaer, Mrs. Stephen
  Wood, Dudley P. K. (president Museum of the City of New York)
  Zoullas, Sophocles N. and Mrs.
- The Bourbon Ball Hotel Plaza [70 negatives in 49 sleeves], 1961 November 2 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Bancroft, Mrs. Thomas N. Jr. (former Melissa Weston)
  Bell, William
  Blackwell, Earl
  Bliss, Mrs. C. Haskell
  Bradley, Mrs. Albert
  Capron, Wallace
  Chickering, Don
  Clinkscales, Harvey
  Cushing, Mrs. Frederick (former Natalie Fell)
  Desmond, Jan (actress)
  Dixon, Jane
  Dodge, Mrs. Horace E. 2nd
  Emery, Raymond G. and Mrs.
  Evans, Harry
  Fabyan, Mrs. Hortense
  Faro, Robert
  Foy, Mrs. Cynthia (former Mrs. Albert Rupp)
  Freimann, Mrs. Lorraine G.
  Garrett, Mrs. Paul
  Geyer, Mrs. Bertram B.
  Gimbel, Adam and Mrs.
  Godfrey, Mrs. Fletcher (co-chairman)
  Hunt, Barbara
  Hurwitz, Col. Is. (buyer, Fine Wines and Liquors, Macy's)
  La Roche, Chester J. and Mrs.
  Lehrer, Mrs. Ruth
  Lewis, Henry 3rd
  Maguire, Marina
  Maguire, Russell and Mrs.
  Marshall, Admiral William
  Morosini, Emil
  Morrison, Mrs. Thomas J.
  Munn, Mrs. Orson D. Sr.
  Nazarenko, Jascha
  Newhouse, Clyde and Mrs. (Maggi McNellis)
  Perry, Mrs. John H. Sr.